# RAVEEN PRABHU

+(65) 9669 3610 — raveenprabhu.com — linkedin.com/in/raveenprabhu — raveenprabhu99@gmail.com

## FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in C#, .NET, and JavaScript, and domain knowledge in accounting and financial systems. Experienced in collaborating with international teams across different time zones. A proven team player with strong communication and collaboration skills, focused on delivering reliable, high-quality solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

## Bachelors of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Aug 2020 - May 2024

National University of Singapore

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Systems, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Cloud Computing

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C, C++, C#, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: .NET, Flutter, React, JavaFx, Flask

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server Cloud Services: Azure, AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda, DynamoDB), Firebase

Other Tech Stack: Linux, Figma, Version Control (Git), Elastic Search, Redis Cache, Unix, Dockers, Visual Studio

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Eye-Share Singapore Pte. Ltd. | C#, .NET, Windows Development

Aug 2022 – Present

- Boosted performance by 40% through implementing advanced threading techniques in C# & .NET for better shared resource management.
- Developed & integrated RESTful APIs to serve real-time data to the front-end based on dynamic user inputs, efficiently handling over 3,000 users and facilitating seamless communication with external systems (SAP, Oracle).
- Spearheaded server and database migration of 12 servers and databases, resulting in minimal downtime and maintaining data integrity for three large clients, each with over 3,000 users.

## Software Engineering Intern | AutoLifeTech Pte. Ltd.

May 2022 - Jul 2022

- Developed a user-friendly dashboard for homeowners to control IoT appliances seamlessly using Flutter and CSS, enhancing user experience and convenience.
- Optimized IoT devices and computer networking protocols, automating homes and offices in 10 condominiums and 3 coworking spaces, which increased efficiency and reduced energy consumption by over 15%.

## **PROJECTS**

CarCare | React, JS, AWS - S3, EC2, DynamoDB, AWS Lambda | github.com/itsraveen/carcare

Apr 2024

• Developed a CEO predictor utilizing machine learning to analyze historical bidding data - hosted on AWS services.

## Static Program Analyzer $\mid C++$

Sep 2023

- Led the development of a Static Program Analyzer (SPA) in a team of 6 using Agile methodologies, ensuring timely delivery and efficient project progression.
- Enhanced performance and responsiveness by applying memoization strategies and adhering to SOLID and DRY principles during critical code refactoring.

 $\mathbf{tApp} \mid \mathit{Java}, \; \mathit{JavaFx} \mid \text{ay2122s1-cs2103-w14-4.github.io/tp}$ 

Oct 2021

• Developed a Teaching Assistant address book manager in Java with JavaFX for streamlined student and lesson details management. Conducted unit-testing with Junit as well as integration testing.

#### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

President | NUS Students' Computing Club

Aug 2021 – Sep 2022

- Led a team of 200 members in organizing over 40 events for students of the NUS School of Computing (SoC).
- Ensured the well-being of over 4,500 students by overseeing and supporting student life in the NUS SoC and maintaining a cordial relationship with the Dean's Office.